bomgar.com 2016-02-17

# Privacy Policy | BOMGAR

Effective Date: 12/09/2015  
Bomgar™ Privacy Policy

This is the web site of Bomgar Corporation.

Because Bomgar Corporation (“Bomgar”, “We”, “Our”, “Us”) respects and is committed to protecting your privacy, we have adopted this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy lets you know how we process and use your personal information. The following policies are only in effect for the Web pages, newsletters, discussion forums and lists and opt-in announcement lists owned and operated by Bomgar Corporation (the "Bomgar Network"). If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Bomgar using the contact information included at the end of this statement.

Bomgar has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information.  TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions.

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site: www.bomgar.com, and does not cover information that may be collected behind the login of our Partner Portal and our Self Service Center Portal as well as our mobile application or through software downloaded from the site.

In order to view our relationship with TRUSTe please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe seal. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at info@bomgar.com or you can reach us by telephone at 1-601-519-0123. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site: www.bomgar.com, and does not cover information that may be collected behind the login on our website or through software downloaded from the site.

Bomgar complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union member countries and Switzerland. Bomgar has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Bomgar's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

Bomgar participates in the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce.  As part of our [participation](http://safeharbor.export.gov/companyinfo.aspx?id=20621) in the safe harbor, we have agreed to TRUSTe dispute resolution for disputes relating to our compliance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Framework. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor you should first contact us (as provided above). If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe by [Internet here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=),  fax to 415-520-3420, or mail to TRUSTe Safe Harbor Compliance Dept., [click for mailing address](http://www.truste.com/about_TRUSTe/contact_us.html). If you are faxing or mailing TRUSTe to lodge a complaint, you must include the following information: the name of company, the alleged privacy violation, your contact information, and whether you would like the particulars of your complaint shared with the company. For information about TRUSTe or the operation of TRUSTe's dispute resolution process, click [here](http://www.truste.com/why_TRUSTe_privacy_services/online-privacy-watchdog.html) or request this information from TRUSTe at any of the addresses listed above. The TRUSTe dispute resolution process shall be conducted in English.

What information are we collecting and how are we collecting it?

When you order products or services, participate in surveys, or apply for a job at Bomgar, we will ask you to provide personal information to complete these transactions. The types of personal information you provide to us on these pages may include contact information such as your name, address, telephone number, and email address; and other unique information such as user IDs and passwords, product and service preferences, contact preferences, educational and employment background, and job interest data. In addition to the information you provide to us, Bomgar may also collect information during your visit to the Bomgar Network through our automatic data collection tools ("Data Collection Tools"), which include cookies, Web beacons, embedded Web links, and other commonly used information-gathering tools. These Data Collection Tools collect certain standard information that your browser sends to our website such as your browser type and language, access times, and the address of the website from which you arrived at the Bomgar Network. These Data Collection Tools may also collect information about your Internet Protocol (IP) address, clickstream behavior and product information. When a visitor requests a page from any web site within the Bomgar Network, our web servers automatically recognize that visitor's domain name and IP address. The domain name and IP address reveal nothing personal about you other than the IP address from which you have accessed our site. Bomgar also collects information from credible third party commercially available sources. This information may include your name, address, email address and demographic data which may be may be used along with the information Bomgar collects when you visit the Bomgar Network.

We use Google Analytics, a third-party tracking service, which uses cookies to track non-personally identifiable information about our visitors to our site in the aggregate to capture usage and volume statistics. Some of our business partners (e.g., Google Analytics) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Bomgar only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third-party.

How do we use your information?

Bomgar collects information to better understand your needs and interests to help deliver a consistent and personalized experience on the Bomgar Network. As a condition to being allowed to download a trial or evaluation software from the Bomgar Network, you consent to being contacted by Bomgar or its representatives to provide you with information about our other products and/or services that we think will be of interest to you. We will give you the opportunity to choose your privacy preferences regarding the communications we send (see below - How do I Select Privacy Preferences). Credit card information is used only for payment processing and fraud prevention. Credit card information and other sensitive personal information required to process a credit decision is not used for any other purpose by our financial services providers or Bomgar and will not be kept longer than necessary for providing the services, unless you ask us to retain your credit card information for future purchases.

User Access and Choice

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove, ask to have it removed from a public forum, directory or testimonial on our site or deactivate it by making the change on our member information page or by emailing our Customer Support at [info@bomgar.com](mailto:info@bomgar.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.  We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Bomgar and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 and Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>[ ](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html)

What are embedded web links and how do we use them?

Some emails from Bomgar may use links designed to lead you to a relevant area on the Web. The redirection system allows Bomgar to change the destination URL of these links, if necessary, and to determine the effectiveness of our marketing initiatives. In emails, such web links may also allow Bomgar to determine whether you have clicked a link in an email, and this information about the interaction may be connected to your personal identity. If you do not want Bomgar to collect information about the links that you click, you can: (1) change your choice about how you receive communications from Bomgar (i.e. choose a text-based version of the message where available); or (2) choose not to click links in an email that Bomgar sends.

Behavioral Targeting/ Re-Targeting

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites.  Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [Here](http://preferences.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)).  Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

(Google AdSense/Adwords) We use Google AdSense to publish ads on this site.  When you view or click on an ad a cookie will be set to help better provide advertisements that may be of interest to you on this and other Web sites.   You may opt-out of the use of this cookie by visiting Google’s Advertising and Privacy page: <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>.

Will we disclose the information we collect to outside third parties?

Bomgar will not share your personal information to others except as described in this Privacy Policy. Bomgar shares personal information in the following ways:

(1) Bomgar retains service providers and suppliers to deliver complete products, services and customer solutions and to assist Bomgar with marketing and communication initiatives. These providers and suppliers include, for example, credit card processors, providers of customer support and live-help, email service providers, automated data processors, and shipping agents. Suppliers and service providers are required to keep confidential the information received on behalf of Bomgar and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for Bomgar.  
(2) Except as described in this Privacy Policy, Bomgar will not share the personal information you provide to Bomgar with non-Bomgar third parties without your permission, unless to: (i) comply with any applicable law, regulation, subpoena, or court order, (ii) respond to authorized information requests of police and governmental authorities; (iii) protect the personal safety of Bomgar employees and third parties on Bomgar property; (iv) help prevent fraud or to enforce or protect the rights and properties of Bomgar; or as a part of a sale, merger or other reorganization of the Company, in which case you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information; (v) or to any other third party without your prior consent to do so.

How do I select privacy preferences?

You may opt out of receiving communications from Bomgar by using one of the following methods:

(1) Select the email "opt out" or "unsubscribe" link, or follow the opt-out instructions included in each email communication  
(2) Return to the Bomgar Web page(s) where you originally registered your preferences and follow the opt-out instructions.  
(3) Write to Bomgar. Be sure to provide your name, email and postal address, and specific relevant information about the Bomgar communications that you no longer wish to receive.

Please note that when you opt out of receiving certain communications, it may affect the services you have chosen to receive from Bomgar where accepting the communications is a condition of receiving the services.

How do we keep your personal information secure?

To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of the information, Bomgar utilizes appropriate physical, technical and administrative procedures to safeguard the information we collect. Bomgar uses resonable security when collecting or transferring sensitive information such as credit card information. Credit card numbers are used only for processing payments and are not used for other purposes. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however.  Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at info@bomgar.com.

Bomgar Community

Our site includes a social networking community from our main site which is used to connect users to each other. In order to use this part of our Web site, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on the registration form and require you to create a user name and password.  We use this information to contact you about the topics on our site in which you have expressed interest and will receive Bomgar's Community letters and other Community promotions.  You may opt-out of receiving these types of communications by reviewing the three options listed under the 'How do I select privacy preferences' section above.

You have the option to provide demographic information (such as income level, gender and birth date) to us; we encourage you to submit this information so we can provide you a more personalized experience on our site.

We would also encourage you to review your Privacy Settings.

Tell-A-Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend [email a friend, refer a friend, send to a friend, email a page, invite a friend] about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address.  We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site.  Bomgar stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at [info@bomgar.com](mailto:info@bomgar.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

Blog

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [info@bomgar.com](mailto:info@bomgar.com).  In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Surveys or Contests

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site.  If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.  The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code).

We use may use a third party service provider to conduct these surveys or contests; that company is prohibited from using our users' personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provide through a contest or survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice.

Links to Other Web Sites

Our Site includes links to other Web sites (including our Community site) whose privacy practices may differ from those of this site. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit.

Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook and Twitter buttons and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

Notification of Privacy Statement Changes

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Contact Us

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy and/or site, please contact us via the information below. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

Our postal address is  
578 Highland Colony Parkway  
Paragon Center, Suite 300  
Ridgeland, Mississippi 39157

We can be reached via e-mail at [info@bomgar.com](mailto:info@bomgar.com) or you can reach us by telephone at 1-601-519-0123.
